Guide to the Dance Program Performance Films, 1990-2012 UA.25.16.0001 UA.25.16.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dance Program Performance films
1990-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
UA.25.16.0001
2 Linear Feet
The Dance Program Performance Films are a video record of the performances put on by the Duke Dance Program from 1990-2012.
Collection Overview
The Dance Program Performance Films were recorded across three different formats: VHS cassettes, mini-DV cassettes, and DVDs. Most of the Dance Program's performances from 1990-2012 are represented. Recurring dance performances include Choreolab performances, November and December dances, Composition Class final examinations, and Ark dances.
Historical note
In the 1970's, dance at Duke, under the excellent guidance of Julia Wray, was housed in a very supportive Physical Education department. The course offerings included two levels of modern dance technique, modern dance repertory, composition, improvisation, and two or three courses in dance history. Two full length concerts as well as 2 or 3 informal events were offered each year. In the late 70's, two levels of ballet technique were added to the curriculum. In the 80's, after dance was moved from Physical Education and placed within the Institute of the Arts, the program developed increased rigor in its training both in the studio and in theory courses. As the number of full time faculty grew from two to seven, the selection of courses increased dramatically.
Adapted from: http://danceprogram.duke.edu/about/history
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Dance Program Performance Films were received by the University Archives as a transfer in May, 2013.
Dance -- Education; Dance -- Performances
- DVDs, 2005-2012
  - ChoreoLab 2012, 2012-04-21/2012-04-22
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0016)
  - November Dances 2011, 2011-11-11/2011-11-12
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0015)
  - ChoreoLab 2011, 2011-04-22/2011-04-23
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0014)
  - November Dances 2010, 2010-11-20/2010-11-21
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0013)
  - ChoreoLab 2010, 2010-04-10
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0012)
  - Across the Threshold 2010 2 of 2
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0011)
  - Across the Threshold 2010 1 of 2
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0010)
  - November Dances 2009, 2009-11-21
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0009)
  - ChoreoLab 2009
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0008)
  - November Dances 2008, 2008-11
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0007)
  - ChoreoLab 2008
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0006)
  - November Dances 2007, 2007-11-17
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0005)
  - ChoreoLab 2007, 2007-04-21
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0004)
  - ChoreoLab 2006
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0003)
  - November Dances 2006, 2006-11-18/2006-11-19
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0002)
  - November Dances 2005, 2005-11-19/2005-11-20
    - DVD (Box 2, Video-disc UA25160001-DVD-0001)
- MiniDV videocassettes, 2001-2008
  - November Dances 2008 Camera 1 Tape 2 Saturday, 2008-11
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0045)
  - November Dances 2008 Camera 2 Tape 1 Sunday, 2008-11
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0044)
  - Orisha Traditions Through Rhythm And Song, 2008-02-23
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0043)
  - ChoreoLab 2008 (Tape 2 of 2), 2008-04-20
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0042)
  - ChoreoLab 2008 (Tape 1 of 2), 2008-04-20
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0041)
  - Across the Threshold 2008 Tape 2, 2008-02-23
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0040)
  - Across the Threshold 2008 Tape 1, 2008-02-23
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0039)
  - November Dances Part II, 2007-11-18
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0038)
  - November Dances Sunday Part I, 2007-11-18
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0037)
  - November Dances Part 3 of 3, 2007-11-18
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0036)
  - November Dances Part 2 of 3, 2007-11-17
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0035)
  - November Dances Part 1 of 3, 2007-11-17
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0034)
  - November Dances Dress Rehearsal Part 2, 2007-11-16
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0033)
  - November Dances Dress Rehearsal Part 1, 2007-11-16
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0032)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday, Part I, 2007-04-22
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0031)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday, Part II, 2007-04-22
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0030)
  - ChoreoLab 2007: Celebrating Clay Tape 1 of 2, 2007-04-21
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0029)
  - ChoreoLab 2007: Celebrating Clay Tape 2 of 2, 2007-04-21
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0028)
  - ChoreoLab 2007: Celebrating Clay Dress Rehearsal, 2007-04-20
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0027)
  - Celta Quinn Lipton Thesis, 2007-04-14
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0026)
  - November Dances Sunday 1 of 2, 2006-11-19
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0025)
  - November Dances Sunday 2 of 2, 2006-11-19
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0024)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday 2 of 2, 2006-04-02
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0023)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday 1 of 2, 2006-04-02
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0022)
  - Ark Dances, 2006
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0021)
  - ChoreoLab Sunday Full, 2005-04-03
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0020)
  - November Dances 2004 1st half, 2004-11-06
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0019)
  - November Dances Sat 2nd & Half Sun 1st half, 2004-11-06/2004-11-07
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0018)
  - Ark Dances, 2004-04-10
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0017)
  - ChoreoLab, 2004-03-28
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0016)
  - November Dances 2003, 2003-11-22
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0015)
  - Kumudini Lakuia Open Rehearsal, 2003-10-08
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0014)
  - K. Lakhiz Guest Choreo, 2003-10-06
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0013)
  - Ark Dances, 2003-04-12
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0012)
  - Ballet ChoreoLab Tape 1, 2003-03-30
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0011)
  - Ballet ChoreoLab Tape 2, 2003-03-30
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0010)
  - Remembering a Wedding, 2002-11-03
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0009)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 2 Tape 1, 2002-11
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0008)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 2 Tape 2, 2002-11
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0007)
  - Ark Dances 2002 #1, 2002-04-12
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0006)
  - Ark Dances 2002 #2, 2002-04-12
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0005)
  - Ballet ChoreoLab 2002 Pt 2 (wide)
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0004)
  - Ballet ChoreoLab 2002 Pt 1 (wide)
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0003)
  - December Dances 2001 (#1), 2001-12-01
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0002)
  - December Dances 2001 (#2), 2001-12-01
    - MiniDV videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-Mini DV-0001)
- VHS videocassettes, 1990-2005
  - November Dances, 2005-11-20
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0053)
  - November Dances, 2005-11-19
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0052)
  - ChoreoLab 2005, 2005-04-03
    Scope and Contents
    Choreolab 2005: 1. Rosetta Rhythms; 2. When the Time Comes; 3. Man in a Room Gambling; 4. Jam/More Responsive Reading; 5. The Run Down; 6. Seruba
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0051)
  - Choreolab 2005, 2005-04-02
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0050)
  - November Dances 2004, 2004-11-07
    November Dances 2004: 1. Studies; 2. Anna's Themes; 3. Chaconne; 4. Fugitive Visions; 5. The Dreamer; 6. Rainbow Etude; 7. Strength and Beauty
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0049)
  - Composition Class Showing, 2004-04-19
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0048)
  - Ark Dances, 2004-04-10
    Ark Dances 2004: 1. Untitled; 2. Taiwanese Aboriginal Dance; 3. Almost a Tango (Excerpts); 4. Em Esaeler; 5. Dance of Chivalry; 6. A Choreographic Offering (Excerpts); 7. Spring Shower; 8. Mballax-Kat [1] (um-belecks-kat)
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0047)
  - ChoreoLab 2004, 2004-03-28
    Choreolab 2004: 1. …Almost a Tango; 2. Common Ground; 3. Element: Unknown; 4. Suite from a Choreographic Offering
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0046)
  - November Dances 2003, 2003-11-22
    November Dances 2003: 1. Arambh; 2. Trans-; 3. Dun Dun Ba; 4. Hip Hop: It's Still Here; 5. Memory/Discovery; 6. More to the Point
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0045)
  - Ark Dances 2003, 2003-04-12
    Ark Dances 2003: 1. Let's Get Loud; 2. Tell Him; 3. A Cappella; 4. Variation from Paquita; 5. Ophidiaphobia; 6. By the Grace of Others; 7. Fever; 8. Manjani
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0044)
  - ChoreoLab 2003, 2003-03-30
    Choreolab 2003: 1. Hi-Fi Fantasies; 2. Take Five; 3. Pop Life; 4. Vigil
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0054)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 1 Tape 1, 2002-11
    November Dances 2002: 1. Two By Fours; 2. Enraptured/Entangled; 3. Felt and Woven; 4. Gran Chimin; 5. Suite from a Choreographic Offering; 6. Manduka Shabdham; 7. Jalidon
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0042)
  - November Dances 2002 Camera 1 Tape 2, 2002-11
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0043)
  - Ark Dances, 2002-04-13
    Ark Dances 2002: 1. Coyote Ugly; 2. Layers; 3. Tunhwang Flying Angel Dance; 4. Shadow Boxer; 5. Are We There Yet?; 6. Don't Cloud Up On Me; 7. Valley; 8. Half Circles; 9. Celtic Vision; 10. The Planets; 11. Ku-ku/Sunu Kick
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0041)
  - ChoreoLab 2002, 2002-03-29/2002-03-31
    Choreolab 2002: 1. Valley; 2. Layers; 3. Cloud 9; 4. Out of the Box; 5. The Planets
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0040)
  - December Dances 2001, 2001-12-01
    December Dances 2001: 1. Hootenanny; 2. O Brother Sun, and Sister Moon; 3. Orphidiaphobia; 4. Womantree; 5. Kathak; 6. Palladio; 7. Culebra
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0039)
  - ChoreoLab 2001
    Chorelab 2001: 1. Fling; 2. Aztec Pony; 3. Man in a Room Gambling; 4. Siga (Go On); 5. Tropical Fantasy in Five Parts; 6. Astral Flight
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0038)
  - December Dances 2000, 2000-12
    December Dances 2000: 1. Valley - Excerpt; 2. Looking Forward; 3. The Purple Waltzes; 4. Interspersion; 5. Middle of the Road; 6. Kunda
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0037)
  - ChoreoLab 2000, 2000-04-08
    Choreolab 2000: 1. Running to Stand Still; 2. Layers; 3. Guide Me, O Thou Great Jehovah; 4. A Man in a Room Gambling; 5. The Roommate; 6. Drum Debt; 7. Valley
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0036)
  - December Dances 1999, 1999-12-04
    December Dances 1999: 1. Concerto Grosso; 2. Grief Divided; 3. Solima Sene Fari; 4. Hidin' in Haydn; 5. Calling; 6. Alder Meadows
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0035)
  - Ark Dances, 1999-04
    Ark Dances 1999: 1. Rhythms in Blue; 2. Untitled; 3. Wan Hua Ying Chun; 4. Romanza; 5. Refining Fire; 6. Ballet Variations; 7. Phase Three; 8. Mwamba II
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0034)
  - December Dances 1998, 1998-12-04
    December Dances 1998: 1. 21 Questions; 2. Spire; 3. Extinct; 4. Option II; 5. Tap Dance; 6. Alleluia For…Whatever; 7. Meditation on Violence #1; 8. Origins Rising/Holding Souls
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0033)
  - Comp. Showings, 1998-12
    - VHS videocassette (Box 2, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0055)
  - Ark Dances, 1998-04-17
    Ark Dances 1998 (April 17): 1. Class; 2. Reflection; 3. Auf Wiedersehen; 4. Parts; 5. Zippers' Suite; 6. Experiment in Texture; 7. The Cuddle Duet; 8. Sorrow's Sojourn; 9. Feather Fan Dance; 10. Blues Related
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0032)
  - Reading, Writing, Representin' Conference Roundtable, 1998-04-11
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0031)
  - Reading, Writing, Representin' Conference Performance, 1998-04-11
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0030)
  - December Dances, 1997-12-06
    December Dances 1997: 1. Danse Macabre; 2. The Return; 3. Memory and Discovery; 4. Palladio (Balletomania); 5. Ridicolezza and Other "R" Words; 6. Jitterbird Remembers; 7. Tangos; 8. Aide; 9. Allegro Misterioso, Trio Estatico; 10. Tulongo
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0029)
  - NC Dance Festival Triangle Night, 1997-09-25
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0028)
  - Ark Dances, 1997-04
    Ark Dances Spring 1997: 1. Divertissement --> Coppelia, Act 3; 2. Swing Low; 3. Right Hand; 4. Stillshot (with 13 Gestures); 5. Elusive Union; 6. Three Hand Reel; 7. Passages
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0027)
  - December Dances, 1996-12-07
    December Dances 1996: 1. Letting Go; 2. Hubba Bubba and Other Dances; 3. Sevillanas; 4. The Whispers of Angels; 5. Test; 6. Louise's Ballet; 7. Lamban: A Tribute to the Legend of Sunjata, the Lion of Mali
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0026)
  - Senior Dance Concert, 1996-04
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0025)
  - Ark Dances, 1996-04-12
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0024)
  - December Dances, 1995-12-01
    December Dances 1995: 1. Sinfonia; 2. Sevillanas; 3. Miscarried Time Abort Bamboo; 4. Autumn; 5. Headless Woman; 6. Some Caucasian Spirituals; 7. Homage to Anna Sokolow; 8. Chrysalis; 9. Redemption
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0023)
  - Composition Class Final, 1995-04-26
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0022)
  - Ark Dances, 1995-04-08
    Ark Dances 1995: 1. Morning Glory; 2. Chinka Chinka Chinka; 3. A Brief History of Tap; 4. Gershwin Medley; 5. American Graffiti; 6. Two Works in Progress; 7. Fairy Tale; 8. Drunk and Gourd
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0021)
  - Four Ballets, 1995-03-31
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0020)
  - Composition Class Final, 1994-12-07
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0019)
  - Faculty/Student Dance Concert, 1994-12-03
    Fall Concert 1994: 1. Give Thanks; 2. I Blink and She's Gone; 3. Summer Seven; 4. Thread; 5. Mr. Brown; 6. Odylic Source; 7. Changeling; 8. "Land of Snow" from the Nutcracker
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0018)
  - Ark Dances, 1994-12-22
    Ark Dances Fall 1994: 1. Shan-Dong Flutter Fan Dance; 2. Mea Culpa; 3. Meat; 4. Hip Hop Junkies; 5. Five Ways to Whoopee; 6. Spiritual; 7. Ziellos Tap; 8. Innocent
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0017)
  - Clay Taliaferro and Friends, 1994-03-18
    Program included in slipcase. Clay Taliaferro and Friends/Dancing: 1. Old Dancing, Arranged; 2. The Purple Waltzes; 3. Plateau…The Words; 4. Shhh!; 5. From Whence, Whereto; 6. I Shall Mingle
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0016)
  - Composition Class Final, 1993-12-08
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0015)
  - Faculty/Student Dance Concert, 1993-12-03
    Faculty/Student Concert 1993: 1. Egun-Gun Masquerade; 2. Someone Is…Standing in the Doorway, Leaving With Us; 3. Unaccompanied; 4. Improvography; 5. Mohawk; 6. Romanza; 7. Untitled; 8. Chaos
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0014)
  - Faculty/Student Dance Concert, 1992-12-03/1992-12-05
    1992 Fall Faculty/Student Concert: 1. Thread; 2. The Awakening; 3. Slave to Love or Fashion?; 4. Romanza; 5. Inwardly Mobile; 6. Heartstrings; 7. And We Dance the Earth's Dance
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0012)
  - Ark Dances, 1993-11-12
    Ark Dances Fall 1993: 1. The Commuters; 2. Tea Leaves Harvest Dance; 3. Scarlet Fever; 4. Shake It Like a White Girl; 5. Unity; 6. Hot and Bothered; 7. Spirit Love; 8. Painting a Dream; 9. Chaos
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0013)
  - Comp Class, 1992-04-30
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0011)
  - Ark Dances, 1992-04-17
    Ark Dances Spring 1992: 1. Avatara…The Last; 2. Time One; 3. Will You Be There; 4. Untitled; 5. That's No Way Out; 6. Fabulous Monsters
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0010)
  - Duke Dance Concert, 1992-04-03
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0009)
  - Duke Dance Concert, 1991-09-27/1991-09-28
    "Doin' Things Together": 1. Odyssey; 2. Luminis; 3. Sweet Suite; 4. Shhhh!; 5. Remaining Fire
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0008)
  - Duke Faculty at UNCG, 1991-09-11
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0007)
  - Ark Dances, 1991-04-11/1991-04-12
    Ark Dances 1991: 1. Wind Fall (excerpt); 2. Moving Forward; 3. Ethnicolor; 4. Trios Intwined; 5. Earth Spirit; 6. Painted Pictures; 7. February Sea; 8. Live Dangerously
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0006)
  - Lorca Dances, 1991-04-05/1991-04-06
    Lorca Dances: 1. En La Noche; 2. Arbole; 3. Shadow Patterns; 4. Ancient Voices of Children
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0005)
  - Julia Wray Dance, 1990-12-01
    Julia Wray Concert: 1. Mesa; 2. Periods of Grace; 3. Fifth French Suite; 4. Buckdancing; 5. Field and Stream; 6. Wedding Cake; 7. Common Law; 8. Fossfates
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0004)
  - Ark Dances, 1990-11-17
    Ark Dances Fall 1990: 1. Isicathulo; 2. Madame, Oui, Monsieur; 3. Mesa; 4. Jammin; 5. Fossfates; 6. Reflections…Sometimes We Forget; 7. Dependence; 8. Transformation; 9. Quotations
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0003)
  - Dance and Drumming, 1990-09-14
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0002)
  - Ark Dances, 1990-04-14
    Ark Dances Spring 1990: 1. Madame, Oui, Monsieur; 2. Vigil; 3. Workin' on a Buildin'; 4. Womansong; 5. Harsher Landscapes, Quest
    - VHS videocassette (Box 1, Video-cassette UA25160001-VHS-0001)